DEVEN SHARMA

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

JDEVEN.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

CONTACT

P: +1 416-200-4467
E: deven.sharma@gmail.com
lightdirection.ca

2119 Lakeshore Boulevard West Etobicoke, Ontario

PROFILE

Empathy comes first in my design process. By understanding pain points, user experience can be substantially improved. If successful, mundane yet critical tasks are transformed into activities that are interesting and straightforward. Software can be a pleasure to use, increasing productivity and engagement.

EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGNER | JULY 2017 - NOV 2019

Innosphere SDG Ltd.

Innosphere specializes in the development and quality assurance testing of commercial and custom software applications, with an emphasis on mobile and web development.

- Lead the creation of consistent experiences across products and platforms through user-centered design processes, including competitor analysis, heuristic evaluations, personas, sitemaps, process flows, wireframes, mock-ups and interactive prototypes.
- Worked closely with product owners, business partners, developers, and data architects to understand business and functional requirements, as well as technical considerations.
- Coordinated design walkthroughs, feedback sessions and usability testing to validate proposed design solutions with stakeholders and end users.

PRODUCT DESIGNER | NOV 2016 - MAY 2017

Proxy Project

Proxy Project specializes in helping organizations create better products, design innovative solutions, accelerate speed to market and predict growth.

- Managed the development of the Kia CPO website, by addressing all the client's database needs and providing clear and concise graphical web data.
- Designed the "Lilypad" mobile insurance application using InVision for wireframes and prototyping, Sketch for design and Principle for animation.
- Sourced, optimized and designed digital content for the Kia CPO website using Adobe Illustrator and Sketch UI Design.

PRODUCT DESIGNER | APR 2016 - NOV 2016

CYC Labs

A Toronto-based digital design and development firm specializing in 3D Animation.

- Worked with the creative and design team to develop the Kia Fleet website using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Optimized the Kia Fleet website for desktop, tablet and mobile implementations using Sketch, Avocode and GitLab Repository Manager.
- Worked closely with the Creative Lead to ensure all usability and experiential goals are achieved while yielding a visual design that's harmonious with the product's style.

EXPERTISE

GRAPHIC DESIGN

Dhotochon

ТПОТОЗПОР
Illustrator
InDesign
DEVELOPMENT
HTML
CSS
Javascript
Javascript
Javascript WIREFRAMING
WIREFRAMING
WIREFRAMING Sketch/InVision

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Bachelor of Science Major: Environmental Science Major: English Literature Minor: Computer Science June 2012